[
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used in React.js to increase performance?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) Virtual DOM is used in React.js to increase performance.",
        "options": [
            "Virtual DOM",
            "Original DOM",
            "Both A and B",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is ReactJS?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) ReactJS is a user-interface framework.",
        "options": [
            "Server-side framework",
            "user interface framework",
            "both a and b",
            "none of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the one which is used to pass data to components from outside",
        "answer": "Answer: D) props are used to pass data to components from outside.",
        "options": [
            "Render with arguments",
            "setState",
            "PropTypes",
            "props"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Who created React.js?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) Jordan Walke created React.js.",
        "options": [
            "Jordan Mike",
            "Jordan Walke",
            "Tim Lee",
            "Jordan Lee"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In which language is React.js written?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) React.js is written in Javascript.",
        "options": [
            "Python",
            "JavaScript",
            "Java",
            "PHP"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Babel?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) Devil is a JavaScript compiler.",
        "options": [
            "JavaScript compiler",
            "JavaScript interpreter",
            "JavaScript transpiler",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the command used to create a react app.",
        "answer": "Answer: B) npm install -g create-react-app is used to create a react app.",
        "options": [
            "npm install create-react-app",
            "npm install -g create-react-app",
            "install -g create-react-app",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following port is the default where webpack-dev-server runs?",
        "answer": "Answer : D) 8080 is the default where webpack-dev-server runs.",
        "options": [
            "3000",
            "3306",
            "3030",
            "8080"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "How many elements can a valid react component return?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) A valid red component can return only 1 element.",
        "options": [
            "1",
            "2",
            "3",
            "4"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "A state in React.js is also known as?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) A state in React.js is also known as the internal storage of the component.",
        "options": [
            "The internal storage of the component",
            "External storage of the component",
            "Permanent storage",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following method is used to access the state of a component from inside of a member function?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) this.values is used to access the state of a component from inside of a member function.",
        "options": [
            "this.prototype.stateValue",
            "this,getState()",
            "this.values",
            "this.state"
        ]
    },
    null,
    {
        "question": "What are arbitrary inputs of components in react also known as?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) Arbitrary inputs of components in react also known as Props.",
        "options": [
            "Elements",
            "Props",
            "Keys",
            "Ref"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In MVC, what does React.js act as?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) ViewIn MVC, React.js acts as the \"View\" (V). React.js is mainly used to create and manage the user interface (UI) components and their interactions in a web application, which is the main responsibility of the View layer in the MVC architecture.",
        "options": [
            "Model",
            "Controller",
            "View",
            "Middleware"
        ]
    },
    null,
    {
        "question": "Among The following options, choose the one which helps react for keeping their data uni-directional?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) FLux helps react for keeping their data uni-directional.",
        "options": [
            "DOM",
            "Flux",
            "JSX",
            "Props"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Using which of the following command can prevent default behaviour at in react?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) preventDefault() is used to prevent default behavior in react.",
        "options": [
            "preventDefault()",
            "avoidDefault()",
            "revokeDefault()",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the smallest building block of React.JS.",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Components are the smallest building blocks of ReactJS.",
        "options": [
            "Props",
            "Elements",
            "Components",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is ReactJS mainly used for building?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) ReactJS is mainly used for building user interfaces.",
        "options": [
            "Database",
            "Connectivity",
            "User interface",
            "Design platform"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following function is used to change the state of react component?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) this.setState() is used to change the state of react component.",
        "options": [
            "this.setState()",
            "this.state()",
            "this.setChangeState()",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the following which acts as the input of class-based component?",
        "answer": "Answer : D) props act as the input of the class-based components.",
        "options": [
            "Factory",
            "Render",
            "Class",
            "props"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the following which is used to create a class inheritance?",
        "answer": "Answer: B)Extends are used to create a class inheritance.",
        "options": [
            "Inherits",
            "Extends",
            "Create",
            "this"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the correct data flow sequence of flux concept.",
        "answer": "Answer: A) The correct data flow sequence of flux concept is :     Action -> Dispatcher -> Store -> View",
        "options": [
            "Action -> Dispatcher -> Store -> View",
            "Action -> Dispatcher -> View -> Store",
            "Action -> Store -> View -> Dispatcher",
            "Dispatcher -> Action -> Store -> View"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Total ways of defining variables in ES6 is?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) There are three ways of defining variables in ES6: let, var and const.",
        "options": [
            "1",
            "2",
            "3",
            "4"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following are two ways to handle data in react?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) State and props is used to handle data in react.",
        "options": [
            "services and components",
            "State and props",
            "state and services",
            "state and component"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the corner which is a must-have for every ReactJS component?",
        "answer": "Answer : A)renderComponent is a must-have for every ReactJS component.",
        "options": [
            "renderComponent",
            "SetinitialComponent",
            "Render",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "ES6 stands for _________",
        "answer": "Answer : C) ES6 stands for ECMAScript 6.",
        "options": [
            "ECMA 6",
            "ECMAJavaScript 6",
            "ECMAScript 6",
            "EJavaScript 6"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the method with refers to the parent class in ReactJS?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) super() refers to the parent class in ReactJS.",
        "options": [
            "this()",
            "super()",
            "iniherits()",
            "self()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "JSX stands for __________",
        "answer": "Answer : A) JSX stands for Javascript XML.",
        "options": [
            "Javascript XML",
            "JSON XML",
            "JSON",
            "Javascript and AngularJS"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The function which is called to render HTML to a web page in react?",
        "answer": "Answer : B)render() is called to render HTML to a web page in react.",
        "options": [
            "ReactDOM_render()",
            "render()",
            "render_DOM()",
            "DOM_HTML()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the functionality of setState?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) setState invoke code after the setState operation is done.",
        "options": [
            "Access the previous state before the setState operation.",
            "invoke code after the setState operation is done",
            "replace this date completely instead of the default merge actionnone of the above",
            "none of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the method which is not a part of ReactDOM?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) ReactDOM.destroy() is not a part of ReactDOM.",
        "options": [
            "ReactDOM.createPortal()",
            "ReactDOM.hydrate()",
            "ReactDOM.destroy()",
            "ReactDOM.findDOMNode()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the correct statement in the context of uncontrolled components in ReactJS?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Source of truth is DOM is correct in the context of uncontrolled components in ReactJS.",
        "options": [
            "source of truth can be anything",
            "source of truth is a component state",
            "source of truth is DOM",
            "none of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In which directory is react component saved?",
        "answer": "Answer : C) React component is saved in js/components in/.",
        "options": [
            "vendor/js/components/",
            "components/js",
            "js/components",
            "vendor/components"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the functionality of a “webpack” command?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) Webpack is a model blunder.",
        "options": [
            "Runs react local development server",
            "transfer files all the JavaScript down into one file",
            "a module blunder",
            "none of the above"
        ]
    },
    null,
    null,
    {
        "question": "In react, the key should be?",
        "answer": "Answer: A)The key should be unique among his siblings only.",
        "options": [
            "Unique among his siblings only",
            "unique in the DOM",
            "Does not requires to be unique",
            "all of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company developed ReactJS?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) ReactJS was developed by Facebook.",
        "options": [
            "Apple",
            "Facebook",
            "Google",
            "Twitter"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the component which should be overridden to stop the component from updating?",
        "answer": "Answer : D) shouldComponentUpdate should be override to stop the component from updating.",
        "options": [
            "componentDidUpdate",
            "componentDidMount",
            "willComponentUpdate",
            "shouldComponentUpdate"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to access a function fetch() from h1 element in JSX?",
        "answer": "Answer : D) The correct command is <h1>{fetch()}</h1>.",
        "options": [
            "<h1>${fetch()}</h1>",
            "<h1>{fetch}</h1>",
            "<h1>${fetch}</h1>",
            "<h1>{fetch()}</h1>"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "When setState() is called inside render() method, which of the following events takes place?",
        "answer": "Answer : D) Stackoverflow error occurs when setState() is called inside render() method.",
        "options": [
            "duplicate key error",
            "repetitive output happiness on the screen",
            "nothing happens",
            "stackoverflow error"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What happens if you render an input element with disabled = {false}?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) It will be rendered as enabled if you render an input element with disabled = {false}.",
        "options": [
            "it will be rendered as enabled",
            "it will be rendered as disabled",
            "it will not be rendered at all",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "When is useReducer used over useState in React component?",
        "answer": "Answer: A)When we want to replace redux, useReducer is used over useState.",
        "options": [
            "When we want to replace redux",
            "when we want to break our production app",
            "when we want to improve performance",
            "none of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "React is a ___________",
        "answer": "Answer: B)React is a JavaScript library.",
        "options": [
            "JavaScript framework",
            "JavaScript library",
            "both a and b",
            "none of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the library which is most often associated with react?",
        "answer": "Answer: C)Jest is most often associated with react.",
        "options": [
            "Sinon",
            "Chai",
            "Jest",
            "Mocha"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is used to handle code-splitting?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) React.lazy is used to handle code splitting.",
        "options": [
            "React.lazy",
            "React.memo",
            "React.fallback",
            "React.split"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is useLayoutEffect used?",
        "answer": "Answer : D) When you need the browser to paint before the effect runs, useLayoutEffect used.",
        "options": [
            "To complete the update",
            "to optimize for all devices",
            "To change the layout of the screen",
            "when you need the browser to paint before the effectors"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following terms commonly described react applications?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Declarative is commonly used to describe react applications.",
        "options": [
            "Imperative",
            "Integrated",
            "Declarative",
            "closed"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is ref used?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Ref is used to directly access the DOM node.",
        "options": [
            "to bind the function",
            "to call a function",
            "to directly access the DOM node",
            "to refer to another JS file"
        ]
    }
]